Preliminary Guide to the Faculty Census Reports, 1933-1987
University Archives Duke University
Faculty Census Reports 1933-1987
Duke University. Office of the Provost.
33 Linear Feet
University Archives, Duke University.
Contains Census Reports by faculty and other instructional staff at Duke University. Reports were administered the the Office of the Provost and Deans of schools and include information about courses, instructors and students. Types of materials include individual reports and bound volumes. Major subjects include Duke University administration, course statistics, and activities of Duke University faculty. Materials range in date from 1933 to 1987.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
Provenance
Received 1980. Accession number: A80-207 (Boxes 1-15)
Received 1986. Accession number: 86-94 (Boxes 18-20)
Received 1989. Accession number: 89-0046 (Boxes 20-22)
Historical Note
As the Duke University's chief academic officer, the Provost has broad responsibilities for advancing the education and research missions of Duke University.
Collection Overview
Contains census reports of faculty and other instructional staff of the College of Arts and Sciences, Engineering, Forestry, Law, Medicine, Nursing, and the Graduate School at Duke University. Reports were administered by the Office of the Provost and Deans of schools. Reports include days, dates, and locations of class meetings, credit hours, instructor name and rank, course title and subject matter, department, number of male and female students, and grade level of students. Materials are arranged in chronological order by semester, then alphabetical order by department, program, and faculty members. Contains both foldered files and bound volumes.
Subject Headings
These and related materials may be accessed under the following subject headings in the Duke University Libraries online catalog.
Duke University -- Administration
Duke University -- Faculty.
Duke University. Office of the Provost.
Education -- North Carolina -- Durham -- Statistics.
Preliminary Container List
- Accession number: 80-207
  - October 1933-March 1939 (Box 1)
  - October 1937-November 1943 (Box 2)
  - February 1944-March 1948 (Box 3)
  - October 194-October 1951 (Box 4)
  - March 1952-October 1953 (Box 5)
  - February 1954-October 1955 (Box 6)
  - February 1957-October 1957 (Box 7)
  - February 1958-February 1959 (Box 8)
  - Fall 1959-Fall 1960 (Box 9)
  - Spring 1961-Spring 1965 (Box 10)
  - Fall 1965-Spring 1967 (Box 11)
  - Spring 1967-Fall 1968 (Box 12)
  - Spring 1969-Fall 1970 (Box 13)
  - Fall 1970-Spring 1972 (Box 14)
  - Fall 1972-Fall 1974 (Box 15)
- Accession number: 86-94
  - Fall 1974-Fall 1976 (Box 16)
  - Fall 1976-Spring 1979 (Box 17)
  - Fall 1979-Fall 1981 (Box 18)
  - Fall 1981-Spring 1983 (Box 19)
- Accession number: 89-0046
  - Fall 1982-Fall 1984 (Box 20)
  - Spring 1985-Fall 1986 (Box 21)
  - Fall 1986-Spring 1987 (Box 22)
Office of the Provost records.
University Archives, Duke University.